Thanks for listening to the Grow Your
Life podcast. My name is Jeremiah Kowski
and on this podcast I talk about ways
for you to grow in your life, your
business to get more clients and to make
more money in your coaching business.
Now today I want to talk about high
ticket. A lot of times there's a
misconception about high ticket and what
it means. What does it mean to sell high
ticket? What does it mean to get high
ticket clients? after building multiple
coaching businesses online, I can tell
you that if you don't have a high ticket
strategy, you're missing it because
that's where a lot of your revenue can
come from and a lot of your profit
margins can come from as well. And now I
know that often times a lot of us as
coaches, we're like, I want to help
people. I don't want to have to just
sell expensive stuff. And I get that.
That's why I have a free podcast. That's
why I have my YouTube channel. But at
the end of the day, I'm in a business to
make money. And so even in my group
coaching program, I don't fully provide
everything to people inside of that
program. I require people also become a
part of my high ticket program. So let
me explain the difference between these
two and how you can actually sell people
for it and how we designed our program
as well as what the purpose of a high
ticket program is. The purpose of a high
ticket program is of course to make more
revenue, but also to provide actually
more access and more value to people.
And I'm going to tell you something that
I was surprised about until I actually
got into the weeds of it. Is
that well, if I don't have a high ticket
program, everybody can just go into a
lower level with me. Um, I'm going to
provide far more value to people. Here's
the problem.
the more money people make and there's a
human phenomenon to
this I can't fully explain it but I have
seen it in action is that when people
make a bit higher of an
investment they are more likely to do
something with it because they feel
obligated to do something because of how
much money they spent. And
so the way that as a
coach, if I don't have a high ticket
opportunity for people, a high ticket
offer, I am
literally preventing my clients
codependently from being able to get the
kind of results that they want because
I'm just saying, well, I give it away in
my lower tiers. I don't want to charge
too much money. I don't want to make it
too expensive for
people. And by saying
that, I am literally trying
to
control another person. And in essence,
I am actually hurting them and their
chances of success. And I didn't realize
this until after I created a high ticket
program of my own and I started to see
that the people who became a client in
that high ticket program got more
results than those that were not. Why?
Bec it's not necessarily because the
value wasn't provided in the lower tier.
Trust me, my wealthy coach academy
program, it's monthly. It's $197 a
month. provides so much and above and
beyond more value than you're going to
find
anywhere in the online coaching
industry. And that is what our clients
say, not just myself saying this, but
the people who work with us say that we
have the single greatest level of
information, support, accountability,
and exactly what you need to get results
inside of my Wealthy Coach Academy
program.
And yet, by the same
token, the people who took advantage of
a high ticket offer with
me got more
results because that increased level of
access. And I believe that
increased
investment caused them to take more
seriously the actions to get those
results.
And so again, if you're thinking, "Oh,
I'm not going to have a high ticket
because I want to help people," you are
actually doing far opposite of that by
not having a high ticket program. Now,
when it comes to selling a high ticket
program, people buy from people who they
trust. And so to get people to join your
high ticket program, you need to build
trust with people. And this is even more
so with a high ticket program. This is
even more true with a program that costs
more is that it takes trust. Trust is
the currency of
business. The ability to get people to
trust you, the ability to move people
when they trust you, to get them to take
action. And so again, if you have a
coaching
program, a group coaching program, a
high ticket
program, trust is what it takes to get
people to buy from you. Now, here's how
I've split it out is I will often have
two tiers. Again, we will have our entry
level tier,
$197 a month. I'll offer a 14-day trial
of
this. This is my Wealthy Coach Academy
program. This is my group program that
everybody can join at any stage right
there. But then I have my high ticket
program which is $900. This is monthly
per month. $197 a month, $900 a month.
This gives people access to still a
group coaching, but also gives them
access to limited amounts of one- on-one
interaction with me through Voxer. the
ability to work with me closer to get in
closer proximity with me. And by the
way, I have an even higher ticket tier
that starts at $5500 a month. This is
where I'm actually running your ads. I'm
actually building out all your landing
pages. I'm actually working with you to
create all of that results. So, those
are the three different tiers, two
different tiers of high ticket and then
mid-tier ticket that I have. And at each
level, it takes a level of trust to get
people to sign up. Now, what's
interesting is the top tier right there
usually is somebody who just wants
somebody to do it for them and they're
already making the kind of money that
they want to
make. This first level of high ticket is
somebody who has gone through my
webinars, gone through my content, they
want the coaching, but they're not quite
ready yet to make the investment for me
to do all the work for them.
So, what they do is they want me to be
able to show them and guide them through
exactly step by step what to do, where
to take each process. And that's what's
in my VIP 101 coaching experience is
that you're able to actually work with
me closely to develop out every aspect
of your business. You're able to work
with me closely to be able to make sure
that things get results. And I'm telling
you, you will get more results inside of
my VIP one-on-one coaching experience
than just by staying in my Wealthy Coach
Academy program. It is
guaranteed. Okay? So by having a high
ticket program, I am providing an
opportunity for you to actually make way
more
results, get way more results out of it.
By creating that chance for you to say,
"Okay, I'm going to make more of an
investment with Jeremiah to go to the
next level of access with him, and
that's going to be the catalyst that's
going to drive me forward." And if you
believe
that, that's exactly what it is. And
your clients, I'm going to flip it for
you, are going to believe the same
thing. You want them to believe the same
thing about what you are offering as
well. Each offer that you make needs to
be driven by a
specific outcome that they can expect, a
result that they can
expect. And by leading with that
outcome, often times as mentors and
coaches, we can lead with our features.
What does it include? How does it work
together? That that's all well, great
and dandy, but it's not what sells
programs.
What is the outcome and the delivered
desired result change and tangible walk
away with that almost like you can hold
it in your
hand
storytellingbased
outcome that came out of the situation
that you're coming out of. And when you
do that, when you bring those things
together, man, it is so much easier to
close a sale. it is so much easier to
get
clients to sell high
ticket. Oftentimes you might need to do
um a phone call with people especially
in the beginning but over time you can
translate that into a webinar or a micro
VSSL that people can watch a video of.
This is something that I'll do is I will
send out a mass series of four or five
videos people can watch to get them to
upgrade to that. Oftentimes, people are
going to come in at a lower tier with
you initially and then they're going to
ascend or upgrade up to the h the next
highest
tier. And so that's
why you want to figure out, okay, of the
people who are in this tier right here,
what do they need more than anything
else? If I could provide that to a
smaller group of people, what do they
need, that's going to help push them
over the edge to get the results that
they want. And now that's what you
promise and
deliver in your next high ticket tier.
Okay? Listen, I know that you can make
it happen because I've seen it happen
with other clients of mine. Grow your
life, everybody, and I'll see you in the
next episode. We'll talk soon.
[Applause]
[Music]